Out of My Mind is a drama, family film directed by Amber Sealey.
Melody Brooks, a sixth grader with cerebral palsy, has a quick wit and a sharp mind, but because she is
non-verbal and uses a wheelchair, she is not given the same opportunities as her classmates.
When a young educator notices her student's untapped potential and Melody starts to participate in
mainstream education, Melody shows that what she has to say is more important than how she says it.
Melody Brooks, played by Phoebe-Rae Taylor.
Diane, played by Rosemarie DeWitt.
Chuck, played by Luke Kirby.
Mr. Dimming, played by Michael Chernus.
Dr. Katherine Ray, played by Courtney Taylor.
Mrs. V., played by Judith Light.
Out of My Mind is a 2024 American coming-of-age drama film based
on the 2010 novel of the same name by Sharon M.
It is directed by Amber Sealey and written by Daniel Stiepleman.
The film stars Phoebe-Rae Taylor (in her screen debut), Rosemarie
DeWitt, Luke Kirby, Judith Light, and Jennifer Aniston.
The film premiered at the 2024 Sundance Film Festival on January 19,
2024, and was
released on Disney+ on November 22, 2024.
The film also won a Peabody Award.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, bullying,
wheelchair user   , coming of age, teenage girl.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking.